window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Computer_Network - Computer_Network — Slot 8 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Computer_Network — Slot 8",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Identify the correct sequence in which the following packets are transmitted on the network by a host when a browser requests a webpage from a remote server,assuming that the host has just been restarted. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>HTTP GET request, DNS query, TCP SYN</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>DNS query, HTTP GET request, TCP SYN</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS query,TCP SYN, HTTP GET request</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>TCP SYN, DNS query, HTTP GET request</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS query,TCP SYN, HTTP GET request</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39572/gate2016-2-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>In an Ethernet local area network,which one of the following statements is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A station stops to sense the channel once it starts transmitting a frame.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The purpose of the jamming signal is to pad the frames that are smaller than the minimum framesize.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>A station continues to transmit the packet even after the collision is detected.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The exponential backoff mechanism reduces the probability of collisionon\nretransmissions.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>The exponential backoff mechanism reduces the probability of collisionon\nretransmissions.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39543/gate2016-2-24#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Anarkali digitally signs a message and sends it to Salim. Verification of the signature by Salim requires <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Anarkali's public key</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Salim's public key.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Salim's private key</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Anarkali's private key</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Anarkali's public key</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39555/gate2016-2-23#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>A sender uses the Stop-and Wait ARQ protocol for reliable transmission of frames. Frames are of size 1000bytes and the transmission rate at the sender is 80Kbps(1Kbps=1000 bits/second). Size of anacknowledgement is 100bytes and the transmission rate at the receiver is 8Kbps. The one-way propagation delay is 100milliseconds. <br>Assuming no frame is lost, the sender throughput is _____bytes/second. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "2500",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39696/gate2016-1-55#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>For a host machine that uses the token bucket algorithm for congestion control, the token bucket has a capacity of 1 megabyte and the maximum output rate is 20 megabytes per second. Tokens arrive at a rate to sustain output at a rate of 10megabytes per second. The  token bucket is currently full and the machine needs to send 12megabytes of data. The minimum time required to transmit the data is _____seconds. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "1.1",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39720/gate2016-1-54#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>An IP datagram of size 1000 bytes arrives at a router. The router has to forward this packet on a link whose MTU (maximum transmission unit)is 100bytes. Assume that the size of the IP header is 20bytes. <br> The number of fragments that the IP datagram will be divided into for transmission is _________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "13",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39712/gate2016-1-53#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Consider that B wants to send a message m that is digitally signed to A. Let the pair of private and public keys for A and B be denoted by \\(K_{x}^{-}\\)\nand \\(K_{x}^{+}\\) for x = A,B, respectively. Let  \\(K_{x}(m)\\)\nrepresent the operation of encrypting m with a key \\(K_{x}\\) and H(m) represent the message digest. Which one of the following indicates the CORRECT way of sending the message m along with the digital signature to A? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>{\\(m,K^{+}_{B}(H(m))\\)}</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{-}_{B}(H(m))}\\)}</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{-}_{A}(H(m))}\\)}</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{+}_{A}(H(m))}\\)}</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{-}_{B}(H(m))}\\)}</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39694/gate2016-1-52#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following is/are example(s) of stateful application layer protocols?<br>\n(i) HTTP <br>\n(ii) FTP <br>\n(iii) TCP <br>\n(iv) POP3 <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(i) and(ii)only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii) and(iii)only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(ii) and(iv)only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>(iv)only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>(ii) and(iv)only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39628/gate2016-1-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following protocols is NOT used to resolve one form of address to another one? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>DNS</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>ARP</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>DHCP</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>RARP</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>DHCP</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39639/gate2016-1-24#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Which layers of the OSI reference model are host-to-host layers? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Transport, session, presentation, application</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Session, presentation, application</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Datalink, transport, presentation, application</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Physical, datalink, network, transport</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Transport, session, presentation, application</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51988/isro2015-58\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>A router uses the following routing table:<br>\\(\\begin{array}{|l|l|l|} \\hline \\text { Destination } &amp; \\text { Mask } &amp; \\text { Interface } \\\\ \\hline 144.16 .0 .0 &amp; 255.255 .0 .0 &amp; \\text { eth0 } \\\\ \\hline 144.16 .64 .0 &amp; 255.255 .224 .0 &amp; \\text { eth1 } \\\\ \\hline 144.16 .68 .0 &amp; 255.255 .255 .0 &amp; \\text { eth2 } \\\\ \\hline 144.16 .68 .64 &amp; 255.255 .255 .224 &amp; \\text { eth3 } \\\\ \\hline \\end{array}\\)<br>Packet bearing a destination address 144.16.68.117 arrives at the router. On which interface will it be forwarded? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>eth0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>eth1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>eth2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>eth3</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>eth2</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3607/gate2006-it-63-isro2015-57\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Which statement is false? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>PING is a TCP/IP application that sends datagrams once every second in the hope of an echo response from the machine being PINGED</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>If the machine is connected and running a TCP/IP protocol stack, it should respond to the PING datagram with a datagram of its own</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>If PING encounters an error condition, an ICMP message is not returned</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>PING display the time of the return response in milliseconds or one of several error message</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>If PING encounters an error condition, an ICMP message is not returned</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51980/isro2015-56\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>A certain population of ALOHA users manages to generate 70 request/sec. If the time is slotted in units of 50 msec, then channel load would be <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>4.25</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3.5</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>450</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>350</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>3.5</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/19453/isro2015-55\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>In a class B subnet, we know the IP address of one host and the mask as given below:<br>IP address: 125.134.112.66<br>Mask: 255.255.224.0<br>What is the first address(Network address)? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>125.134.96.0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>125.134.112.0</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>125.134.112.66</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>125.134.0.0</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>125.134.96.0</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51717/isro2015-54\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>An ACK number of 1000 in TCP always means that <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>999 bytes have been successfully received</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>1000 bytes have been successfully received</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1001 bytes have been successfully received</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/19790/isro2015-53\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
